Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Moving Images Collection FILMS.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Transport Workers Union of America Films, 1930-1977; 34.5 Linear Feet in 16 record cartons and 177 film cans; 13.3 Gigabytes in 18 digital files
  - Subseries I.B. Video Reproductions, 1930-1967
    - Broadcast Master Tape 40, 1930-1966; cuid1031 (Box 14, Betacam sp cuid1031)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union demonstrating against Fifth Avenue Coach Company; street scenes in midtown Manhattan and upper east side; conflict between workers and police; poverty; scenes from inauguration of Franklin D. Roosevelt; Program from the national public affairs television series on a TWU strike against New York City's private bus lines; campaign statement from Michael Quill endorsing Democratic mayoral candidate Robert F. Wagner, Jr.; Luncheon honoring William O'Dwyer; Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr. makes speech to CIO Council during his campaign for U.S. Senate.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 00:34:48
    - Broadcast Master Tape 41, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0942)
    - Broadcast Master Tape 42, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0941)
    - Broadcast Master Tape 43, 1955-1960; cuid37017 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37017)
      Includes the following clips: Senator Wayne Morse speaks about his opposition to the Kennedy-Landrum-Griffin bill; Former New York City mayor William O'Dwyer speaks out in favor of organizing civil service workers; Rally sponsored by the labor union District 65 and the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People to protest the murder of Emmett Till; Art show by members of the labor union, District 65; meeting of members of labor union District 65, RWDSU to decide whether to strike against Stern's Department store.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 41 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 44, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0940)
    - Broadcast Master Tape 45, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0939)
    - Broadcast Master Tape 46, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0943)
    - Color Tape 1, Undated (Box 15, Digital betacam 001_0738)
      Transfer from Betacam SP
    - Color Tape 1, 1930-1961; cuid1032 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid1032)
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 01:00:22
      Includes the following clips: May Day rally and demonstration; young Pete Seeger performing; International Workers Order (IWO) picnic; May Day parade, Union Square; New York City May Day parade; New York City Labor Day parade.
    - Color Tape 2, 1967; cuid37013 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37013)
      Includes the following clips: Buses, bus drivers, bus passengers; traffic; subway trains, subway train equipment; views of New York City from elevated subway train; Airport baggage and baggage handlers; airplane maintenance mechanics; jet and propeller airplanes and helicopters.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 54 minutes
    - Color Tape 3, 1967; cuid37014 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37014)
      Includes the following clips: Elevated subway trains and New York City landscapes shot from elevated subway trains; subway train repair shop; airport baggage handlers.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 28 minutes
    - Color Tape 4, 1967; cuid37015 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37015)
      Includes the following clips: Railroad train maintenance workers; gas utility workers; Transport Workers Union's Railroad Division president talking with railroad workers.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 27 minutes
    - Color Tape 5, 1930-1949; cuid37016 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37016)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union election; rally with speakers; transport workers' demonstration at New York City's City Hall protesting the demolition of elevated subway lines.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 32 minutes
    - First Pass - Broadcast Quality Master #1, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0491)
    - First Pass - Broadcast Quality Master #2, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0490)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 1, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0669)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 1-N, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0670)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 2, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0668)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 3, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0667)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 4, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0666)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 5, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0665)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 6, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0664)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 7, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0663)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 8, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0662)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 9, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0706)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 10, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0697)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 11, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0696)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 12, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0695)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 13, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0694)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 14, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0691)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 15, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0672)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 16, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0698)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 17, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0671)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 18, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0700)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 19, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0699)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 20, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0705)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 21, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0704)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 22, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0703)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 23, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0702)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 24, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0701)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 25, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0693)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 26, Undated (Box 13, Vhs 001_0692)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 27, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0584)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 28, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0583)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 29, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0582)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 30, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0581)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 31, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0580)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 32, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0579)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 33, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0578)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 34, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0577)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 35, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0576)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 36, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0575)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 37, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0594)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 38, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0593)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 39, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0592)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 40, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0591)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 41, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0590)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 42, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0589)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 43, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0588)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 44, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0587)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 45, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0586)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 46, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0585)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 47, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0602)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 48, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0601)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 49, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0600)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 50, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0599)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 51, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0598)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 52, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0597)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 53, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0596)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 54, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 001_0595)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 55, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0641)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 56, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0640)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 57, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0639)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 58, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0638)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 59, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0637)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 60, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0636)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 61, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0635)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 62, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0634)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 63, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0633)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 64, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0632)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 65, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0651)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 66, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0650)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 67, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0649)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 68, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0648)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 69, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0647)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 70, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0646)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 71, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0645)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 72, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0644)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 73, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0643)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 74, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0642)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 75, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0661)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 76, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0660)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 77, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0659)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 78, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0658)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 79, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0657)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 80, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0656)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 81, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0655)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 82, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0654)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 83, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0653)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 84, Undated (Box 12, Vhs 001_0652)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 85, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0489)
      Transfer from VHS
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 86, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0488)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 87, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0487)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 88, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0486)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 88 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0566)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 89, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0485)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 89 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0565)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 90, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0484)
    - First Pass - Reference Tape 90, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0554)
    - Historical Footage --50th Anniversary, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0493)
    - Historical Footage -- The Best is Yet to Come, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0495)
    - Historical Footage -- Life of a Union, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0494)
    - Historical Footage -- Years of Challenge, Undated (Box 5, Vhs 001_0492)
    - Master 1, Undated (Box 15, Vhs 001_0737)
    - Reference Tape 1 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0505)
    - Reference Tape 1-N (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0506)
    - Reference Tape 2 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0504)
    - Reference Tape 3 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0503)
    - Reference Tape 4 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0502)
    - Reference Tape 5 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0501)
    - Reference Tape 6 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0500)
    - Reference Tape 7 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0499)
    - Reference Tape 8 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0498)
    - Reference Tape 9 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0497)
    - Reference Tape 10 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0516)
    - Reference Tape 11 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0515)
    - Reference Tape 12 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0514)
    - Reference Tape 13 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0513)
    - Reference Tape 14 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0512)
    - Reference Tape 15 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0511)
    - Reference Tape 16 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0510)
    - Reference Tape 17 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0509)
    - Reference Tape 18 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0518)
    - Reference Tape 19 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0517)
    - Reference Tape 20 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0526)
    - Reference Tape 21 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0523)
    - Reference Tape 22 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0525)
    - Reference Tape 23 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0524)
    - Reference Tape 24 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0522)
    - Reference Tape 25 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0521)
    - Reference Tape 26 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0520)
    - Reference Tape 27 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0519)
    - Reference Tape 28 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0508)
    - Reference Tape 29 (Dub), Undated (Box 6, Vhs 001_0507)
    - Reference Tape 30 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0455)
    - Reference Tape 31 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0454)
    - Reference Tape 32 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0459)
    - Reference Tape 33 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0458)
    - Reference Tape 34 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0457)
    - Reference Tape 35 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0456)
    - Reference Tape 36 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0463)
    - Reference Tape 37 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0462)
    - Reference Tape 38 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0461)
    - Reference Tape 39 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0460)
    - Reference Tape 40 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0464)
    - Reference Tape 41 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0465)
    - Reference Tape 42 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0466)
    - Reference Tape 43 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0467)
    - Reference Tape 44 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0468)
    - Reference Tape 45 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0469)
    - Reference Tape 46 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0470)
    - Reference Tape 47 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0471)
    - Reference Tape 48 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0472)
    - Reference Tape 49 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0473)
    - Reference Tape 50 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0474)
    - Reference Tape 51 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0475)
    - Reference Tape 52 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0476)
    - Reference Tape 53 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0477)
    - Reference Tape 54 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0478)
    - Reference Tape 55 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0479)
    - Reference Tape 56 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0480)
    - Reference Tape 57 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0481)
    - Reference Tape 58 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0482)
    - Reference Tape 59 (Dub), Undated (Box 4, Vhs 001_0483)
    - Reference Tape 60 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0544)
    - Reference Tape 61 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0553)
    - Reference Tape 62 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0552)
    - Reference Tape 63 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0551)
    - Reference Tape 64 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0550)
    - Reference Tape 65 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0549)
    - Reference Tape 66 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0548)
    - Reference Tape 67 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0547)
    - Reference Tape 68 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0546)
    - Reference Tape 69 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0545)
    - Reference Tape 70 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0564)
    - Reference Tape 71 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0563)
    - Reference Tape 72 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0562)
    - Reference Tape 73 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0561)
    - Reference Tape 74 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0560)
    - Reference Tape 75 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0559)
    - Reference Tape 76 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0558)
    - Reference Tape 77 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0557)
    - Reference Tape 78 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0556)
    - Reference Tape 79 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0555)
    - Reference Tape 80 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0574)
    - Reference Tape 81 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0573)
    - Reference Tape 82 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0572)
    - Reference Tape 83 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0571)
    - Reference Tape 84 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0570)
    - Reference Tape 85 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0569)
    - Reference Tape 86 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0568)
    - Reference Tape 87 (Dub), Undated (Box 9, Vhs 001_0567)
    - Tape 51, Undated (Box 14, Betacam sp 001_0935)
- Series II. Films on Organized Labor and the Political Left, 1925-2005; 19.5 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons, 31 film cans, 1 cassette box, 1 manuscript box, and 1 card box
  Series II. Films on Organized Labor and the Political Left (1925-2002) includes programs and event recordings produced and distributed by labor and leftist organizations, mainly on the topics of socialism, communism, civil rights, and labor organizing. Organizations represented in this series include the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), the Jewish Labor Committee, the Socialist Party of the Untied States, the United Auto Workers (UAW), the Communications Workers of America (CWA), the Seafarers International Union (SIU), the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE), the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), the United Steelworkers Union, the American Postal Workers Union (APWU), United Voice, and United Financial Employees. This series also includes works by individual filmmakers, such as Louis W. Kellman's Tales From Tamiment about Camp Tamiment, John Albok's footage of New York City during the Great Depression, and recordings of New York City parades in the early twentieth century. These films provide insight into the history of labor and leftist movements in New York and frequently include candid portrayals of a range of professions, neighborhood, landmarks, and daily life in the 1930s-1960s.
  This series is arranged chronologically with film elements from the same production or event grouped together.
  - The International Labor Organization, circa 1925-1935 (Film canister c99, 16mm film reels 001_0348, 001_0349)
    Reviews the history of the International Labor Organization (ILO). Includes shots of some of the organization's officers. Titles appear in French and English simultaneously.
  - John Albok's Documentary Footage of New York, circa 1929-1955; cuid43062 (Box 34, 16mm film reels 001_0335)
    Footage shot by photographer John Albok of New York City and its citizens, much of it during the Depression. Includes shots of homeless people, a May Day march, African American workers, children at play, parades, track and field events, Central Park, and the Hindenberg.
  - Eugene V. Debs: Labor's Martyr, 1934 (Film canister c98, 16mm film reels 001_0355, 001_0356)
    Biographical sketch consisting mostly of stills and titles. Distributed by the Socialist Party National Headquarters, Chicago.
  - Mass Tribute to Buenaventura Durruti, 1936; cuid43107 (Film canister c101, 16mm film reels 001_0350)
    This is a memorial to Buenaventura Durruti (1896-1936), an anarchist militia leader on the Republican side of the Spanish Civil War. Narrated by Emma Goldman, who was the CNT-FAI's official representative for propaganda in English.
  - May Day in New York City -- Bernard Katz, 1936; cuid9323 (Box Shared Tamiment 170, 16mm film reels 001_0747)
  - Born Equal, circa 1940s (Film canister c193, 16mm film reels 001_0063)
    Australian film discussing some of the main features of the United Nations Declaration of Rights.
  - Assembly of New York State Federation of Labor Convention Parade, August 12, 1939; cuid45124
    These are nitrate films.
    Produced by Columbia Pictures under jurisdiction of IATSE, Affiliated with American Federation of Labor.
    - Reel 1, cuid45125 (Film canister c200, 35mm film reels 001_0451)
    - Reel 2, cuid45126 (Film canister c199, 35mm film reels 001_0452)
  - The House I Live In, circa 1940s (Film canister c186, 16mm film reels 001_0212)
    A dramatised short film opposing religious and ethnic prejudice as "un-American." Stars Frank Sinatra as himself. Distributed by Young America Films, NYC and written by Albert Maltz.
  - One People, 1946 (Box 25, 16mm film reels 001_0448)
    Animated film about immigration in the United States. Opening title and credits are missing. Produced for the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith - Foreign Language Department.
  - The Battle of Wall Street, circa 1947 (Box 22, 16mm film reels 001_0443)
    Story of a strike by Local 205, United Financial Employees, AFL (a section of the Office Employees International Union). Visual contents and narration emphasise the role of the Seafarers International Union in supporting and assisting with the strike. Includes striking footage of picket lines and rallies in front of both the New York Stock Exchange and the Curb Exchange, as well as police knocking down strikers with clubs.
  - Brotherhood of Man, circa 1948 (Film canister c193, 16mm film reels 001_0060, 001_0061)
    Animated film
  - Tales From Tamiment, 1949
    Tribute to Camp Tamiment, the resort in the Poconos run by and for New York City's Rand School of Social Science from the 1920's through the 1950's. Includes footage of young adults engaged in a wide range of outdoor recreation, and footage of Socialist Party members Bertha Mailly, Ben Josephson, and Algernon Lee. Produced by produced by Louis W. Kellman.
    - Film (Film canister c100, 16mm film reels 001_0783, 001_0784)
    - "A" Wind Silent Color Release Print (Film canister 001_0786, 16mm film reels 001_0786)
    - "B" Wind Color Internegative (Film canister 001_0787, 16mm film reels 001_0787)
    - Silent Answer Print (Film canister 001_0785, 16mm film reels 001_0785)
    - Video (Box 8, Digital betacam 001_0733)
      Transfer from 16mm film
  - Nos Maisons d'Enfants, 1949
    Documentary produced by the Jewish Labor Committee to show its members how their contributions were being used to house children who survived the Holocaust in a French orphanage.
    - Composite Print, cuid43019 (Box Shared Tamiment 136, 35mm film reels 001_0724, 001_0725)
    - Release Print (Box Shared Tamiment 136, 35mm film reels 001_0726, 001_0727)
    - Video (Box 8, Digital betacam 001_0718)
      Transfer from 35mm print with optical sound
  - This is the SIU, circa 1949-1954 (Box 22, 16mm film reels 001_0444, Box 27, 16mm film reels 001_0434)
    Promotional film for the Seafarers International Union of North America, Atlantic and Gulf District, detailing its advantages, benefits and services offered.
  - What's Happening in Harlem, circa 1949; cuid1092 (Box Shared Tamiment 133, Film canister c185, 16mm film reels 001_0719)
    Produced by the Communist Party USA for the re-election campaign of NY City Councilmember Ben Davis. Directed by Richard Frank and created with the assistance of people in the Harlem community.
  - The High Wall, circa 1950s (Film canister c221, 16mm film reels 001_0767)
    This film illustrates the origins and effects of ethnic prejudice in the United States through the story of two adolescent boys from different ethnic groups. Sponsors of the film include the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, the Columbia Foundation, Office of Public Instruction--State of Illinois, and the Department of Mental Health -- State of Illinois.
  - The Challenge, 1951 (Film canister c225, 16mm film reels 001_0762, Film canister c222, 16mm film reels 001_0763)